hello everybody Frankie Freitas here
welcome to another week of hollow talk
the Dr Jay Ong interview is coming up in
just a moment I just want to point one
thing out I'm going to give Dr Jang a
fair Shake here he was in Venezuela and
he just got back so uh the show was not
put up on Sunday it's going up on
Tuesday the 31st so what I'm going to do
is the next Hollow talk show is not
going to be this Sunday the next Holo
talk is going to be next Tuesday April
7th
and then we will go back to Sundays
after that so tune in next week Tuesday
night April 7th for the New Hollow talk
show and then we'll get back on to
Sunday's beginning April 12th once again
Dr jown's interview Ryan over a little a
little over 20 minutes long it's a nice
interview he talks about his work with
color holography holography and
education a little bit about
integration even a few comments on the
agfa situation so it's a very
interesting interview so I want to thank
you for tuning in and let's just get
right into the interview and I'm not
going to come back on after it's over so
I'll say goodbye now and thank you very
much for tuning in to hola talk and
thanks for your patience this week for
me getting it up a little bit late
here's the Dr jaeong interview
Dr Jane this is Frankie Freitas how are
you oh good good very good to have you
on the phone do you have a few minutes
yeah you last week I was in no man's
land though you took a little vacation
oh a big one actually yeah did you have
some fun well I took my two sons and I
uh took a week-long clinic on high wind
uh ocean windsurfing that sounds pretty
good to me really very challenging but
we have summer like weather here today
same temperature here as in Venezuela
yeah Allentown PA today we hit about 84
85 degrees today well I guess you didn't
need to think of the case I could still
use the water there is about the same
temperature
uh we're talking to Dr Jay on who is
with Lake Forest College
and Dr Jay Young also runs the
holography workshop programs and the
Symposium the International Symposium
for display holography what's new out
there that you can tell us about that's
uh hot off the grill do you have
anything that's absolutely possible
that we report and ask the CNN interview
US on is uh we can now make Holograms
image you know have the same color as
the object it stays the same color no
matter what angle you look at it has
both vertical and horizontal Parallax
and does not fade away when you look at
large angles
so in other words it's the same as
having the real thing in that in a box
so uh we think that's pretty new and
making
holographic Optical elements you like
make a hologram of a mirror what
that mirror apparently in the inside the
glass actually reflects quite light
holographic Optical elements in three
color we think there are many
applications where are you doing the
full color holography at a series
Studios somewhere around in the we're
doing it at Lake Forest College right at
the college right the center for
photonic studies when is the next
Symposium coming up when is that going
to be uh at the New Millennium oh really
every three years we have uh okay so two
things so last year we just had the
sixth one I see and we had 22 countries
I have not been out there yet well well
you know there's always the next time
I'm sorry I've never been 32 years old
I've never been up there yeah it's not
so far you know yeah I guess I could
drive you know what people do is uh
a naked part of a vacation
people from Europe they just take their
family and after the Symposium of before
they go see the Grand Canyon that's
great well what we can do in 2000
because 2000 is still pretty a long way
maybe I can come out with all the studio
broadcasting equipment we can do some
live broadcast
I'm sure by that time uh internet will
be even more fantastic
Beyond imagination right now I think now
do you have your workshops every year or
are they every two years you've been
having it since 1971. every year every
year but for the first time I'm going to
take a sabbatical this summer
because I have never taken the summer
off
since this year I retired from teaching
in narratives so instead I do research
only which allows me to have a
completely free schedule before I chose
this last week to go and surfing because
that's the high wind season with the El
Nino going on down in Margarita Island
you're certainly like resting oh yeah
yeah
so
tell us a little bit about you know the
researcher doing that the full color
holography is very interesting how many
lasers
we take a blue collar green color and
red color lasers three of them
using dichroic the beam Splitters
combine of the three beams into one so
it's very fantastic to see a white laser
beam
incredible and uh with that one beam we
do Tennessee Holograms exactly the way
you do one color symbol you put a full
color object on the other side of the
whole graphic plate and expose it once
and develop it if someone wanted to see
a full color hologram where are some of
the key places perhaps number one visit
my website we
show quite a few of them so that's out
we have a gallery here in Lake Forest
College of course that's open to the
public every day we show some of the
first ones we made here four years ago
and uh
but the CNN program uh you want me to
give the address
yes you go ahead and give the address
and let me remind the listeners that
there's there will be a link right on
the whole to a page right now as you're
listening to this show you can click on
that link and go to the Lake Forest
College webpage for Dr Jones lab and the
real audio player will continue to play
in the background while you can take a
look at all the Fantastic work that
they're doing out there so watch
and give them the web address in case
uh HTTP
colon slash slash
www dot
Bell FC Dot
edu slash
physics
slash
holography flash okay we allow you to a
lot of choices to visit our gallery to
look at the description of our work and
detail scientific reference
now you've been involved with education
for for privately since the beginning
when you got involved with holography
one of your focuses was not only on the
ecology level education but on junior
high school and high school education as
well
how do you feel
is being represented in the schools now
do you think it's grown or has it sort
of people in my judgment
the educational application of
holography is the area that will be
constant because education is constant
no matter what happens to the economy no
matter what happens to what's new at all
education is key and allography having
involving itself
with three direct Nobel prizes in
physics but Litman Nobel Prize in 1908
the Brock
Nobel Prize in 1915 the Garbo and Nobel
Prize in 1971 mixed holography a very
basic subject meaning is not a trick not
a fad it is good science yes so I had
always been interested in uh making it
understandable so in about 11 years ago
the Thomas Edison Foundation
funded a project in which I wrote a
holography
project book for children for 12 year
olds
and in it we just teach them how to make
seven kinds of holograms at home
right now using a total budget of three
hundred dollars meaning about the money
you need to buy a fair camera yes but
the 300 you buy your laser and all the
Arctic film plates
or everything you need to make those
Holograms so uh I also make videos so my
project had been to well
some schools get those booklets this is
a non-profit basis you know it's a two
dollar book so the whole the philosophy
is
let children learn naturally meaning do
it first then when they are interested
they'll start wondering how does it work
then they have to find out how rainbows
or how soap bubbles give color all the
basic the how seashells you know have
all those nice colors and so forth and
it all these ideas add together equal to
a Tennessee hologram
It's a Wonderful opportunity to bring
the science students together with the
creative students as well because in
schools usually these two uh
this program so to speak I don't think
of these as science or other or whatever
you is just something to do and they
some students who do it as art some
would do this crap so I'm going to do
the signs you know they can decide yes
what it is and uh
I have been doing school programs all
around the country and uh I'm doing
teacher projects meaning on Saturdays
every year
a science student from junior high or
high school always have a so-called
Institute day
but during that day I would teach the
science students how to make Holograms
so then they can of course teach
students locally the the objective of
the whole project is to make holography
a basic part of the science curriculum
curriculum in junior high schools
in other words everybody who have made a
hologram when it have gone through
junior high but they know what the
principles are involved at that time
that's the time before they uh kind of
look at signs in the wrong way
they find out that Faith this even this
is science I couldn't believe it it's
actually fun my friends told me science
cannot be fun you know
and so at age 12 she's about when you
should show them that signs are
everything if you do it with a degree of
dedication they're all fun
I get a lot of students that listen to
this program and let's just imagine an
eighth grade student out there and
they're interested in Holograms and
holography would you encourage them to
follow through on that products you know
so that everything they need what about
as a career choice they want to say they
want to grow
I never tell a student to become a
holographer never never and that reason
for that is uh the reason is I telling
them to do it the way they want to learn
to play the violin you don't necessarily
want to be a concert violinist
you are enriching your life a few people
may end up doing it because you find it
uh that you are so dedicated to it that
you wouldn't mind living that life
but I always advise student to broaden
the Horizon do holography as a project
take the pace also do some projects in
art do some projects in literature yes
then you will know what you like
in the next 10 years do you think
holography would be a serious career
choice for someone it certainly is the
science fair choice right now now here
again I thought if they are interested
in holography I tell them to broaden
their scientific base so that they can
shift anytime a laterally you know into
our life for example the big
kitchen and holography in the next 10
years is computer memory yes each
holographic Optical element for control
light inside the computer chip
the distributed information from one
chip to another via light
that's the important news even now the
most important uses of holography uh you
know in my I have a pine nut I always
wear cheap watches because I lose them
one-on-one shipping
but there's a hologram in in there that
you're looking right through
really I used to when you push the
button at night to look at what time it
is there would be one little bright
light on one corner and spread out to
the other side and you say it's out
right now there's a hologram layer in
there that's expressed the light evenly
throughout the entire space of my watch
it's a hologram nobody knows about that
I did not know about that on the Timex
watch yep the Motorola uh cell phone you
put it on at night there's a hologram on
the on under the Glass isn't that
interesting in other words in lots of
places in a CD player there's a hologram
inside to split the light
send the light to different places you
know and grocery store
in other words Holograms are already in
many places people don't know and in the
future in many other places you don't
know
that's something and that's whole area
so I tell students they can have fun
making Holograms of pictures to learn
maybe that's their profession make art
image artistic images but by learning
one thing you automatically are learning
a million things to relate you know one
learning to another how generic
learnings are
that one physical law applies to
infinite number of things
and then be able to be flexible when you
see an application in hoe do that in
interferometry do that
so uh in that sense the holography grows
in in diverse fields that it is now kind
of invisibly doing uh
in front of your eye literally that we
don't we're not even aware of do you
think the um I think the situation is
going to have any detrimental effect on
holographic education in the United
States I think I'm an optimist I wrote
an editorial for the
proceedings of the volume being
published just last month by the spie
of the conference that we had last
summer and by the title of my
introduction was holography is one of
Renaissance
what I say is access withdrawal actually
ignited a forest fire which is a bad
thing right
but after a forest fire New Growth takes
place I see it clears down and that's
exactly what's going on act for
dominated the scene for 25 years so no
one else will even get in and bother to
make good film and plays so we stayed
status quo no color Holograms I mean two
color Holograms but by their withdrawing
now suddenly we find other sources from
Germany from Russia from Japan and China
and they're better than ever
in other words that's a Renaissance yes
and the upon now is in a game of making
photopolymer in full color we do that by
the way we use Dupont full color uh Polo
polymer and make copies of the Holograms
for your full color hologram right it's
like a mass-produce them
so
in other words there's going to be a a
new life New Millennium for holography
using new and better materials with more
wide open applications now you have a
business which you have had for many
years into graph right
yes yes uh early in my career when I
stopped teaching especially children
hologram they always want to find out
what can I buy the film at that time you
know only you can buy it only in bulk a
whole roll of this a whole big box of
them and so forth but the science fair
project
student is not going to have the money
or the need for large quantities so we
decided at home look we'll sell you one
square the foot of film that's all you
need
well it's another grow and grow and
become the complete business and we
integraf now supply to the whole world
our biggest customer last year was
Australia no kidding all right
and so we also got the dealership from
DuPont to sell their Omnitech 706. they
only give two dealerships in the whole
world at that time so uh that's integraf
so we now assemble a kit for Learners of
any age you want to spend minimum amount
of money to start why waste money by
buying all the new gadgets you don't
even know what they are
so using the simplest thing learn seven
projects first then you know what you
need next to learn the next project so
so uh we still aim at education our
customer base is schools universities
and people want to learn holography so
we make videos show you how to do it and
other written material what to do after
that little booklet you know why don't
you let everyone know your email address
that maybe listen they may be looking
for materials my name if T my initial
and then my last name
j-e-o-n-g with no space
t-j-e-o-n-g at
AOL.com
that we can give people complete
catalogs and we even give advice when
people have trouble they just ask me
questions in the internet and I tell you
here's what you I think you've done
wrong you know
[Music]
I also include a link with your name
the whole talk page so if they click on
my name yeah when they click on your
name they'll get your email address
how's that so that uh
what I'll do is I'll create a link on
the holotalk page sure sure where your
name will be listed and if they click on
your name they will get an email form
that they can request information about
your products with integral right that's
right okay right I appreciate that
anything else you want to let the
listeners know about uh before we wrap
this up
well uh I I tell I I'm a professor in a
liberal arts college for a reason
I tell all young people to
make sure you brought in your education
and not start narrowing down too early
make sure you read history with
literature
do music and make some holograms for fun
and then when you have done
abroad Base education then you choose
what is the best that suits you
so I don't sell holography at all I sell
it that's part of the thing that I can
do
to help
people to get into this particular area
in addition to other areas that's very
wise I hear you're quite the violinist
as well I play into Orchestra I'm a
concert Master of the College of chamber
orchestra and I play first violin in a
semi-professional Orchestra and I enjoy
it enormously and I went surf
with my children I can keep up with them
how do you how old are your sons and uh
so I that's my philosophy of Life how
old are your sons but there are 30 and
32. okay and I'm 66. I I have three
daughters 18 17 and 15. wow
to do things together yeah the oldest
ones who wear a college physics major so
I hope she doesn't wow yes that's great
what college uh Georgie Court College
which is a private women's college in
New Jersey I'm for private uh liberal
arts colleges yes because there we pay
attention to each individual
and My Philosophy is go to a good small
liberal arts college and then go to a
bank go graduate school that's that's
the advice that she received as well and
she's doing pretty good I believe in
that program well Dr Jalen it was a
pleasure speaking with you great
pleasure and uh I hope you log on and
hear the interview
well congratulations on your new life I
can't wait till I can start my new life
interesting one and I certainly you're
very devoted to what you're doing and
that is a sign that you enjoy what
you're doing yeah I have a great time
right thank you very much for being
again okay good night all right bye
foreign